Hello, and welcome to Lesson 2 of this introduction to calculus with Wolfram U.
您好，欢迎来到Wolfram U的微积分入门课程第二课。
The topic for this lesson is functions. Let’s begin with a brief overview of the lesson.
本课的主题是函数。让我们从本课的简要概述开始。
Last time, we learned that calculus is all about change, so you can have changing speed
上次，我们了解到微积分与变化有关，因此您有不断变化的速度
or changing volume, and then you can apply calculus to study such phenomena.
或不断改变的体积，然后您可以应用微积分研究此类现象。
But a little more precisely, calculus is about quantities that change with respect to other quantities.
但更确切地说，微积分是关于相对于其他量变化的量。
For example, the distance traveled by a car changes with respect to time,
例如，汽车行驶的距离随时间而变化，
so you think of time as being an independent variable, and the distance depends upon the time taken.
因此您将时间视为一个独立变量，而距离取决于所花费的时间。
Or the surface area of a cylinder varies with respect to the radius and the height of the cylinder.
再一个例子，圆柱的表面积相对于圆柱的半径和高度而变化。
What we need is a precise way of defining such changes, and that’s what we’ll do in this lesson.
我们需要的是定义此类变化的精确方法，这就是我们在本课中将要做的。
We’ll show you how to do this using functions in the Wolfram Language. Let’s begin by
我们将向您展示如何使用Wolfram语言中的函数来执行此操作。我们从
by defining a function, but before doing that, I need to speak about sets.
定义一个函数说起，但是在此之前，我需要谈谈集合。
A set is a collection of objects. For example, you could talk of the set of even, positive numbers—
集合是对象的集合。例如，我们可以讨论一组偶数，正数-
2, 4, 6, 8, 10, et cetera—and then an element of this set is an object that belongs to it.
2、4、6、8、10等），此集合中的元素就是属于它的对象。
For example, 2 is an element of the even, positive numbers, while 3 is not an element of that set.
例如，2是偶数，正数的元素，而3不是该集合的元素。
Well, a function is a rule that assigns to each element x in a set X exactly one element,
好的，函数是一个规则，它将集合X中的每个元素x映射给一个元素，
called f[x], in a set Y. You think of them as being x and y as in this example.
在集合Y中称为f [ x ] 。在此示例中，您将它们视为x和y。
You’ve got a function Sin[x], which is a trigonometric function, and its graph,
您有一个函数Sin [ x ]（它是一个三角函数）及其图形，
its plot is a wavy form, but the point here is that this x axis over here is the domain
它的曲线是波浪形的，但是这里的要点是这个x轴是
of the function, and that is all the real numbers, while the function values over go between
函数的定义域，即所有实数，而函数值在
−1 and 1, so that gives you the range of this function, −1 to 1, while the entire y axis
-1和1，因此可为您函数的值域，-1至1，而整个y轴
is called the codomain. You have a function, and then you have the domain, the codomain and its range.
称为到达域。您有一个函数，然后有了定义域，共域及其值域。
The question is how do you do make such functions in the Wolfram Language?
问题是您如何使用Wolfram语言实现此类功能？
Here’s how we do it. We have a function f[x] = x^2, so for every x over here,
以下是我们的方法。我们有一个函数f [ x ] = x ^ 2，所以这里的每个x
it doesn’t matter what x is; you simply square that number or expression. For example,
x是什么都没关系；您只需将该数字或表达式平方即可。例如，
f[2] is clearly 4. But you can also have a function that depends upon two variables, x and t,
f [2]显然是4。但是您也可以具有一个依赖于两个变量x和t的函数。
so that’s like a pattern for x and that’s a pattern for t. Here’s a function g, and then you can
所以就像x的模式，而t的模式。这是一个函数g，然后您可以
define the function and then find its values. The g[2, 3] is 33, so when x is 2 and t is 3,
定义函数，然后找到其值。的g [2，3]是33，所以当X是2和t是3，
then the value of the function is 33.
那么该函数的值为33。
Okay. Another thing you might want to do with a function is to find what the graph
好的。您可能要对函数进行的另一件事是
of the function looks like. The graph is just the set of all ordered pairs x and f[x] for that function.
查看函数的图形。该图只是该函数的所有有序对x和f [ x ]的集合。
You think of that as being pairs of x’s and y’s.
您认为这是x和y数对。
Here is a plot of the function f[x] = x^2 between 0 and 10, but you can also put in
这是函数f [ x ] = x ^ 2在0到10之间的图，但是您也可以直接在Plot函数中
x^2 directly over here in the Plot function and get back just the same result.
直接输入x ^ 2，并获得相同的结果。
Okay. The question now is how do you find the value of a function for other expressions?
好的。现在的问题是如何找到其他表达式的函数值？
Let’s say f[x] is x^2. Then the value of f[x + 1] is (x + 1)^2, but you might want to
假设f [ x ]是x ^ 2。那么f [ x + 1]的值是（x + 1）^ 2，但是您可能想要
simplify that a little bit, so you can do Expand of the result and get back the expanded version.
简化一点，因此您可以对结果进行展开并获取展开后的表达式。
Or you can apply the Expand function a little later, and get back just the same result.
或者，您可以稍后再应用Expand函数，然后返回相同的结果。
Over here you’ve got a function g, and you can put x + y for x, and then expand
在这里，您有一个函数g，可以将x + y表示为x，然后展开
and get back the result. Okay. The question is now in how many ways can you define a function?
并得到结果。好的。现在的问题是，您可以通过几种方式定义一个函数？
Well, first of all, you could use a table of values like over here.
好吧，首先，您可以使用此处的值表。
There’s a function which squares a number, so 1^2 is 1, 2^2 is 4, et cetera, and you get back
有一个平方函数，所以1 ^ 2是1，2 ^ 2是4，等等，然后返回
a function from this table of values. Or you could describe the graph of the function.
此值表中的函数。或者，您可以描述函数图。
This graph over here tells you that for every value of the side, you have side squared on the y axis.
此图在此告诉您，对于side变量的每个值，它们均在y轴上平方。
Or you could just use an algebraic formula and get the same function. Functions can be defined
或者，您可以只使用一个代数公式并获得相同的函数。Wolfram语言中
in various ways depending on the situation and problem.
我们能根据不同的情况和问题而采用不同的办法来定义函数。
Now here’s a practical example to put together what we’ve done so far.
现在，这是一个实际的例子，可以汇总我们到目前为止所做的事情。
You want to find the cost of a metal box which has volume of 100 and whose height is twice its length,
您想求出一个容量为100且高度为其长度的两倍的金属盒的价格，
given that the top and bottom cost $5 per square centimeter while the sides cost $8.
考虑到顶部和底部的成本为每平方厘米5美元，而侧面的成本为8美元。
Okay. The cost is going to be 5 times the top and bottom area plus 8 times the side area.
成本将是顶部和底部面积的5倍，再加上侧面面积的8倍。
That’s the cost function. Now you know the volume is length times width times height,
这就是成本函数。现在您知道体积是长度乘以宽度乘以高度，
and that’s the relationship given to you, height is twice the length, so you can plug that into
这就是交代给您的数量关系，高度是长度的两倍，因此您可以将其插入
the equation for the volume and get back an expression for w, the width, in terms of the length.
表示体积的方程式，然后返回表示长度w的表达式。
Once you’ve done that, then the entire cost of the box can be written in terms of l, the length.
完成此操作后，便可以用长度l来表示盒子的全部成本。
You can use that to compute the cost of the box when its length is 10 cm, and the answer is $3,410.
您可以使用它来计算盒子长度为10厘米时的成本，答案是3,410美元。
Okay. Now in this example, if you look at the function for the box cost,
好的。现在在此示例中，如果您查看盒装成本函数，
then you could plug in a length of −1. That still works, but of course that’s not a very meaningful length;
那么您可以插入-1的长度。仍然有效，但是长度并不是很有意义。
it’s a negative number. You could also try to plug in 0.
这是一个负数。您也可以尝试插入0。
This time, Mathematica and the Wolfram Language will certainly complain and tell you that
此时，Mathematica（Wolfram Language）将会告诉您
this is not allowed; it’s an indeterminate answer. We have a function called FunctionDomain
这是不允许的；这是一个不确定的答案。我们有一个叫做FunctionDomain的函数
which will definitely try and isolate the problems for you. It says over here that
这肯定会为您解决问题。它给出
the length of the box should either be negative or positive–not zero like over here—
盒子的长度应该为负数或为正数-而不是像这里的零-
but of course you know that in practice, negative lengths are not useful,
但是您当然知道，在实践中，负长度是没有用的，
so you do need to use some common sense when you find the domain of a function.
因此，在找到函数的域时，确实需要使用一些常识。
The context of the problem is everything.
问题的实质是一切。
Okay. Let’s go on now and talk about how to decide whether something is a function.
好的。现在让我们继续讨论如何确定某物是否为函数。
A function, recall, has to give you exactly one element, f[x], for every x.
回想一下，对于每个x，函数必须给您恰好一个元素（也就是一一对应）f [ x ] 。
Here’s an example of a plot which is not a function, and why is that?
这是一个非函数的示例图，为什么呢？
Because for every number over here, you get back two numbers on the y axis.
因为对于这里的每个数字，您都会在y轴上返回两个数字。
Every number between −1 and 1 gives you two numbers vertically. If you were to draw a vertical line,
-1和1之间的每个数字都会为您提供两个垂直初值方向的值。如果要画一条垂直线，
then that vertical line will cut the plot at two points, and so this relation over here is not a function.
则该垂直线将在两点处切断该图，因此此处的关系不是函数。
The vertical line test is a very useful way of finding out whether a given plot gives a function or not.
垂直线测试是判断给定图形是否是一个函数图的一种非常有用的方法。
Having done all that, let’s now talk about all the different kinds of functions.
完成所有这些之后，让我们现在讨论所有不同类型的函数。
A very nice, simple kind of function is a piecewise function. For example, here is
一中非常好的，简单的函数是分段函数。例如，这里是
the real absolute value of x. The absolute value is a V-shaped function, but you could also use
x的实际绝对值。绝对值是V形函数，但您也可以使用
the built-in Piecewise function to do just the same thing. Piecewise will say that the value should be
内置的逐段函数可以完成相同的操作。分段函数表明值对应该是
−x for −x, and x otherwise. That’s the same function, but now defined manually
− x代表− x，x大于0则为x。这个函数和上面的函数是相同的，只是现在被用Piecewise指令来手动定义了。
using Piecewise. Another kind of function that is quite useful in practice is a symmetric function.
在实践中非常有用的另一种函数是对称函数。
You can have an even function which has a plot that’s the same on the left and the right, so to speak.
您可以研究一个偶数函数，其左右两侧的图相同。
The value of f[−x] is the same as f[x]. Or you can have an odd function in which the plot now looks like
˚F [ - X ]的值和˚F [ X ]相同。或者，您可以具有一个奇函数，它的图现在看起来像这样
it’s negative on the left and positive on the right in this case, so the value of f[−x] is −f[x].
在这种情况下，它的左边为负，右边为正，因此f [ -x ]的值为-f [ x ]。
Finally, you could have a functions which increase or decrease.
最后，您可以研究递增的函数或者递减的函数。
Here is the square function, and if you plot it, it first decreases, it goes down and then increases.
这是平方函数，如果绘制它，它会先减小，然后减小然后增大。
But here’s an example of a much simpler function which neither increases or decreases;
但是，这里有一个简单得多的函数（既不增加也不减少）的示例。
it’s just nice and flat and constant. There are a wide range of functions in calculus,
它是一个很好的 水平的常值函数。微积分中有多种函数，
and each of them lets us solve different kinds of problems. That’s the end of the lesson.
它们中的每一个都可以让我们解决各种问题。我们这节课即将结束。
Just to summarize, functions tell us how quantities change with respect to other quantities.
概括地说，函数告诉我们一些量相对于其他量如何变化。
You can use either words or tables or graphs or formulas to define a function.
您可以使用自然语言或表格，图形或公式来定义函数。
If you’re given a graph, the question might be is this a function or not? Well, you can apply
如果给您一张图，可能的问题是要求您判断这是不是一个函数图。这样的话，你可以使用
the vertical line test. Then finally, functions can be piecewise or even or odd
垂直线测试。最后，函数可以是分段的，也可以是对称或反对称
or increasing or decreasing, and all kinds of other classifications, but all of them prove
或增加或减少的，当然也有更多其他分类，但事实证明，
to be useful in practice. In the next lesson, we’ll go over the basic functions which we require in calculus,
这些函数在实践中都很有用 在下一课中，我们将介绍微积分所需的基本函数，
but before doing that, do review today’s lesson, go over the exercises and make sure you follow functions,
但是在进行这些之前，请先复习今天的课程，仔细阅读练习题并确保您掌握了函数这个主题，
because they are at the very heart of calculus. Once you know functions,
因为它们是微积分的核心。一旦你懂得函数，
you can begin the study of calculus. I’ll stop over here.
你将能轻松学习微积分。今天的课程就到这里